<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Sadie Wisotsky: Bioinfomatician</title>
<link>https://srwis.github.io/personal_site/</link>
<atom:link href="https://srwis.github.io/personal_site/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>Babbling about Bioinformatics</description>
<generator>quarto-1.8.27</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Publications</title>
  <dc:creator>Sadie Wisotsky</dc:creator>
  <link>https://srwis.github.io/personal_site/posts/papers/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 





<section id="peerreviewed-publications" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="peerreviewed-publications">Peer‑Reviewed Publications</h2>
<section id="section" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="section">2026</h3>
<ul>
<li><p>🧪 <strong>Cancer Immunology Research (AACR)</strong> <strong>Reuschel, E. L., Sylvester, A., Marcus, S., Wisotsky, S., Dolgoter, A., Reed, K. S., Tan, G. S., Skolnik, J. M., Gillespie, E. (2024).</strong> <em>Treatment of Recurrent Respiratory Papillomatosis with DNA immunotherapy INO-3107 induces activation and enrichment of pro-inflammatory CD4+ T cell responses in blood and airways of patients with clinical response</em> https://doi.org/10.1158/2326-6074.IO2026-A060</p>
<details>
<summary>
<p><strong>Abstract</strong></p>
</summary>
<p>Recurrent respiratory papillomatosis (RRP) is a chronic, debilitating disease of the airway primarily caused by infection with human papillomavirus (HPV) types 6 and/or 11 and characterized by recurrent, benign tumor growth with potential for malignant transformation. Current standard of care consists of repeated surgical removal of papillomas, which can lead to lasting airway damage and impaired vocal function. Thus, a non-surgical approach to treat RRP is paramount. Previously, we described CD8+ T cell responses associated with clinical response to INO-3107, a DNA immunotherapy designed to generate T cells capable of targeting HPV-infected cells, in adult RRP patients during a Phase 1/2 trial (NCT04398433). Here, we describe CD4+ T cell responses in these patients.</p>
</details></li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="section-1" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="section-1">2025</h3>
<ul>
<li>🧪 <strong>Nature Communications</strong><br>
<strong>Morrow, M. P., Gillespie, E., Sylvester, A., Amin, M. R., Belafsky, P. C., Best, S. R., … Wisotsky, S. R., Marcus, S., Reuschel, E. L., Reed, K. S., Weiner, D. B., Dallas, M., Skolnik, J. M. (2025).</strong><br>
<em>DNA immunotherapy for recurrent respiratory papillomatosis (RRP): Phase 1/2 study assessing efficacy, safety, and immunogenicity of INO‑3107.</em><br>
https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-56729-6</li>
</ul>
<details>
<summary>
<strong>Abstract</strong>
</summary>
Recurrent respiratory papillomatosis (RRP) is a chronic airway disease caused by HPV. In this Phase 1/2 study, INO‑3107, a DNA immunotherapy targeting HPV‑6/‑11, was well‑tolerated and showed clinical benefit, reducing surgical interventions in participants and generating antigen‑specific T‑cell responses that correlated with clinical outcomes.
</details>
<hr>
</section>
<section id="section-2" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="section-2">2024</h3>
<ul>
<li>🧪 <strong>Cancer Immunology Research (AACR)</strong><br>
<strong>Gillespie, E., Sylvester, A., Marcus, S., Reed, K., Reuschel, E. L., Wisotsky, S., et al (2024).</strong><br>
<em>Reduction in Surgical Interventions for the Treatment of Recurrent Respiratory Papillomatosis by INO-3107 is Associated with Enriched Macrophage, Dendritic cell and T cell Signatures in Patient Airways</em><br>
https://aacrjournals.org/cancerimmunolres/article/12/10_Supplement/A005/748902</li>
</ul>
<details>
<summary>
<strong>Abstract</strong>
</summary>
Recurrent respiratory papillomatosis (RRP) is a debilitating chronic disease of the airway caused by Human Papillomavirus (HPV) characterized by recurrent benign tumor growth with the potential for malignant transformation. The current standard of care requires frequent surgeries, the sequalae of which have long-standing negative impacts on airway and vocal function. Treatments that avoid surgery targeted against HPV6 and/or HPV11 (known etiological agents of RRP) are thus an area of need. Here we describe the results of a Phase 1/2 trial of INO-3107, a DNA therapy designed to elicit T-cell responses against HPV-6 and HPV-11, in adults with RRP (NCT04398433). Methods: Peripheral blood mononuclear cells (PBMCs) were assessed by IFNg ELISpot and TCRb sequencing of complementarity determining region 3 (CDR3). Formalin fixed paraffin embedded papilloma tissue obtained prior to INO-3107 treatment as well as at the end of the 52-week study was assessed by RNA sequencing. Data were analyzed using Ingenuity Pathway Analysis (IPA) and R. Overall clinical response (OCR) was defined as a reduction in surgical interventions recorded on study as compared to the year prior to study. Results: The OCR of the trial was 81.3%. Analysis of PBMCs longitudinally across the study via ELISpot confirmed induction of T cell activity specific to HPV-6 as well as HPV-11. TCRb sequencing of CDR3 regions indicated significant T cell clonal expansion in all patients. IPA based assessments indicated a number of significantly enriched immune pathways in airway tissue at the end of study relative to pre-treatment, spanning both innate and adaptive immune responses. For the former, enriched pathways were inclusive of recruitment (z=2.3, p=1.00e-10), migration (z=2.4, p=6.50e-15), quantity (z=2.3, p=1.37e-10), and response (z=3.0, p=5.85e-07) of antigen presenting cells, indicative of an innate inflammatory response. Upregulated genes included macrophage and dendritic cell associated transcripts such as IFNg, CIITA, XCR1, CD14 and others. For the latter, homing (z=2.4 , p=7.77e-06), quantity (z=2.7, p=6.27e-21), signaling (z=3.9, p=3.16e-12), and cytotoxicity (z=2.6, p=1.18e-06), of T cells were all significantly enriched, indicating a robust influx of activated T cells into airway tissue. T cell associated transcripts included CD3D/E/G, PRF1, CD8A, GZMA, and others. Conclusions: INO-3107 provides clinical benefit to adults with RRP, is well tolerated, and generates an antigen-specific immune response against HPV types 6 and 11. In total, 100% of patients on trial demonstrated T cell activity in blood after administration of IN0-3107, inclusive of antigen specific cytokine production and significantly expanded T cell populations. Moreover, treatment induced an inflammatory response in patient airway tissues, inclusive of signatures of macrophages, dendritic cells and T cells. Importantly, this activity was associated with overall clinical response
</details>
<hr>
</section>
<section id="section-3" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="section-3">2021</h3>
<ul>
<li>🟢 <strong>PLoS ONE</strong><br>
<strong>Lucaci, A. G., Wisotsky, S. R., et al.&nbsp;(2021).</strong><br>
<em>Extra base hits: Widespread empirical support for instantaneous multiple‑nucleotide changes.</em><br>
https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0248337</li>
</ul>
<details>
<summary>
<strong>Abstract</strong>
</summary>
This study provides empirical evidence for instantaneous multiple‑nucleotide substitutions across genomic datasets, challenging assumptions of strictly single‑nucleotide change models in evolutionary analyses.
</details>
<ul>
<li>🟣 <strong>Molecular Ecology</strong><br>
<strong>Cui, R., Tyers, A. M., Juzar Malubhoy, Z., Wisotsky, S. R., et al.&nbsp;(2021).</strong><br>
<em>Ancestral transoceanic colonization and recent population reduction in a nonannual killifish from the Seychelles archipelago.</em><br>
https://doi.org/10.1111/mec.15982</li>
</ul>
<details>
<summary>
<strong>Abstract</strong>
</summary>
Phylogenomic and species distribution evidence supports transoceanic dispersal events and recent population decline in Seychelles killifish, with genomic signals of relaxed developmental gene selection.
</details>
<hr>
</section>
<section id="section-4" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="section-4">2020</h3>
<ul>
<li>🔵 <strong>Molecular Biology and Evolution</strong><br>
<strong>Wisotsky, S. R., Kosakovsky Pond, S. L., Shank, S. D., &amp; Muse, S. V. (2020).</strong><br>
<em>Synonymous site‑to‑site substitution rate variation dramatically inflates false positive rates of selection analyses.</em><br>
https://doi.org/10.1093/molbev/msaa037</li>
</ul>
<details>
<summary>
<strong>Abstract</strong>
</summary>
Ignoring synonymous rate variation across sites can inflate false positive detection of natural selection in molecular data. Incorporating this variation improves evolutionary inference reliability.
</details>
<ul>
<li>🔵 <strong>Molecular Biology and Evolution</strong><br>
<strong>Kosakovsky Pond, S. L., Wisotsky, S. R., Escalante, A., et al.&nbsp;(2020).</strong><br>
<em>Contrast‑FEL: A test for differences in selective pressures at individual sites among clades.</em><br>
https://doi.org/10.1093/molbev/msaa263</li>
</ul>
<details>
<summary>
<strong>Abstract</strong>
</summary>
Contrast‑FEL provides a method for identifying differences in selective pressures at specific sequence sites between phylogenetic clades.
</details>
<ul>
<li>🔵 <strong>Molecular Biology and Evolution</strong><br>
<strong>Kosakovsky Pond, S. L., Poon, A. F. Y., Wisotsky, S. R., et al.&nbsp;(2020).</strong><br>
<em>HyPhy 2.5 ‑ A Customizable Platform for Evolutionary Hypothesis Testing.</em><br>
https://doi.org/10.1093/molbev/msz197</li>
</ul>
<details>
<summary>
<strong>Abstract</strong>
</summary>
HyPhy 2.5 is a phylogenetic software platform enabling flexible hypothesis testing via molecular evolutionary models.
</details>
<hr>
</section>
<section id="section-5" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="section-5">2014</h3>
<ul>
<li>🟡 <strong>Phytopathology</strong><br>
<strong>Parker, J. K., Wisotsky, S. R., et al.&nbsp;(2014).</strong><br>
<em>Viability of ‘Candidatus Liberibacter asiaticus’ prolonged by addition of citrus juice to culture medium.</em><br>
https://doi.org/10.1094/PHYTO‑10‑13‑0264‑R</li>
</ul>
<details>
<summary>
<strong>Abstract</strong>
</summary>
Addition of citrus juice extended viability of the plant pathogen <em>Candidatus Liberibacter asiaticus</em>, improving culture conditions for experimental study.
</details>
<hr>
</section>
</section>
<section id="theses-dissertations" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="theses-dissertations">Theses &amp; Dissertations</h2>
<ul>
<li>🎓 <strong>Wisotsky, S. R. (2019).</strong> <em>Statistical Methods and Genomic Data Analyses for Detecting Natural Selection.</em> Ph.D.&nbsp;Dissertation, North Carolina State University.<br>
https://www.proquest.com/openview/d6709c9e0ac6a25b4547fe1937e80fc5/1?pq‑origsite=gscholar&amp;cbl=18750&amp;diss=y</li>
</ul>
<details>
<summary>
<strong>Abstract</strong>
</summary>
This dissertation develops statistical approaches for detecting natural selection in genomic datasets, focusing on model robustness and evolutionary inference techniques.
</details>
<hr>
</section>
<section id="research-focus-areas" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="research-focus-areas">Research Focus Areas</h2>
<ul>
<li>Evolutionary model development<br>
</li>
<li>Statistical inference of natural selection<br>
</li>
<li>Synonymous rate variation and codon models<br>
</li>
<li>Cancer immunology and epigenetic regulation<br>
</li>
<li>Bioinformatics and clinical trial data analysis</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<p><em>Click “Abstract” under each entry to expand details.</em></p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>research</category>
  <category>publications</category>
  <category>bioinformatics</category>
  <guid>https://srwis.github.io/personal_site/posts/papers/</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Hyphy tutorials</title>
  <dc:creator>Sadie Wisotsky</dc:creator>
  <link>https://srwis.github.io/personal_site/posts/HyPhy-videos/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 





<p>As part of my time as a postdoc at IGEM in Temple University, I recorded a series of youtube video for the <a href="https://hyphy.org/">HyPhy</a> software package.</p>
<p>This video describe how to use BUSTED[S], a model I developed in graduate school while at NCSU. The paper for which can be read <a href="https://academic.oup.com/mbe/article/37/8/2430/5739973?login=false">here</a>.</p>
<div class="quarto-video ratio ratio-16x9"><iframe data-external="1" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FRcJjYIcnY8" title="" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></div>
<p>The rest of the tutorial videos can be found on the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@hyphyvision7202">HyPhy Youtube</a>.</p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>communication</category>
  <category>tutorials</category>
  <guid>https://srwis.github.io/personal_site/posts/HyPhy-videos/</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Upload pins for use with data explorer app</title>
  <dc:creator>Sadie Wisotsky</dc:creator>
  <link>https://srwis.github.io/personal_site/posts/pins_tut/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 





<section id="purpose" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="purpose">Purpose</h2>
<p>This is a walkthrough of how I set up a pins folder and added data to it. The tags and folder structures combine with a coming shiny app that allows you to filter data sets before downloading them. This is essentially my first attempt at an ETL pipeline using R only and prior to pushing for a switch to an SQL data warehouse and true ETL pipeline.</p>
<section id="get-your-data" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="get-your-data">Get your data</h3>
<p>first read the data in that you want to upload</p>
<div class="cell">
<div class="code-copy-outer-scaffold"><div class="sourceCode cell-code" id="cb1" style="background: #f1f3f5;"><pre class="sourceCode r code-with-copy"><code class="sourceCode r"><span id="cb1-1"><span class="fu" style="color: #4758AB;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">library</span>(tidyverse)</span>
<span id="cb1-2"></span>
<span id="cb1-3">iris.dat <span class="ot" style="color: #003B4F;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">&lt;-</span> <span class="fu" style="color: #4758AB;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">data</span>(iris)</span></code></pre></div></div>
</div>
<p>take a peak at the data and also here is where you’d do any data manipulation to it (add columns, calculations, etc. )</p>
<div class="cell">
<div class="code-copy-outer-scaffold"><div class="sourceCode cell-code" id="cb2" style="background: #f1f3f5;"><pre class="sourceCode r code-with-copy"><code class="sourceCode r"><span id="cb2-1"><span class="fu" style="color: #4758AB;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">summary</span>(iris)</span></code></pre></div></div>
</div>
</section>
<section id="connect-to-the-sharepoint" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="connect-to-the-sharepoint">connect to the sharepoint</h3>
<div class="cell">
<div class="code-copy-outer-scaffold"><div class="sourceCode cell-code" id="cb3" style="background: #f1f3f5;"><pre class="sourceCode r code-with-copy"><code class="sourceCode r"><span id="cb3-1"><span class="fu" style="color: #4758AB;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">library</span>(pins)</span>
<span id="cb3-2"><span class="co" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">#library(Microsoft365R)</span></span>
<span id="cb3-3"></span>
<span id="cb3-4">site <span class="ot" style="color: #003B4F;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">&lt;-</span> <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"[placeholder]"</span></span>
<span id="cb3-5">folder <span class="ot" style="color: #003B4F;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">&lt;-</span> <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"../pins/tutorial"</span> <span class="co" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">#change the folder based on where you wish the pins to end up. can also make a new folder for a new study or project</span></span>
<span id="cb3-6"></span>
<span id="cb3-7"></span>
<span id="cb3-8"></span>
<span id="cb3-9"><span class="co" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;"># only needed if pins are stored remotely on a sharepoint site</span></span>
<span id="cb3-10"><span class="co" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;"># can also change this if data is on google drive, aws, etc</span></span>
<span id="cb3-11"><span class="co" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">#sp &lt;- get_sharepoint_site(site_id = site)  </span></span>
<span id="cb3-12"><span class="co" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">#doclib &lt;- sp$get_drive()</span></span>
<span id="cb3-13"><span class="co" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">#board &lt;- board_ms365(doclib, folder) </span></span></code></pre></div></div>
</div>
<p>can take a peak at the pins that already exist in this folder. Note that the pins listed here will not necessarily reflect the pins listed in the app because of the Upload = TRUE metadata step we will show later.</p>
<div class="cell">
<div class="code-copy-outer-scaffold"><div class="sourceCode cell-code" id="cb4" style="background: #f1f3f5;"><pre class="sourceCode r code-with-copy"><code class="sourceCode r"><span id="cb4-1"><span class="fu" style="color: #4758AB;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">pin_list</span>(board)</span></code></pre></div></div>
</div>
</section>
</section>
<section id="create-new-pin" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="create-new-pin">create new pin</h2>
<p>here we are going to use pin_write to create a new pin in the folder. For the app, I’ve tried to include column names, a short description of the data, and some informative tags you will see how they get added here. additionally in the custom metadata section I have added a flag called “Upload”, if “Upload” = TRUE then the data is meant to appear in the data delivery app. If “Upload” is FALSE or missing, it will not appear in the data delivery app.</p>
<div class="cell">
<div class="code-copy-outer-scaffold"><div class="sourceCode cell-code" id="cb5" style="background: #f1f3f5;"><pre class="sourceCode r code-with-copy"><code class="sourceCode r"><span id="cb5-1">cnames <span class="ot" style="color: #003B4F;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">&lt;-</span> <span class="fu" style="color: #4758AB;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">colnames</span>(iris) <span class="co" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;"># get column names</span></span>
<span id="cb5-2"></span>
<span id="cb5-3">desc <span class="ot" style="color: #003B4F;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">&lt;-</span> <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"default IRIS data for pins upload vingette"</span></span>
<span id="cb5-4"></span>
<span id="cb5-5"><span class="fu" style="color: #4758AB;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">pin_write</span>(board,</span>
<span id="cb5-6">          iris,</span>
<span id="cb5-7">          <span class="at" style="color: #657422;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">name =</span> <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"IRIS"</span>,</span>
<span id="cb5-8">          <span class="co" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">#title = meta$title,</span></span>
<span id="cb5-9">          <span class="at" style="color: #657422;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">description =</span> desc,</span>
<span id="cb5-10">          <span class="at" style="color: #657422;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">metadata =</span> <span class="fu" style="color: #4758AB;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">list</span>(</span>
<span id="cb5-11">            <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"Column Names"</span> <span class="ot" style="color: #003B4F;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">=</span> cnames,</span>
<span id="cb5-12">            <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"Upload"</span> <span class="ot" style="color: #003B4F;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">=</span> <span class="cn" style="color: #8f5902;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">TRUE</span> <span class="co" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">#change if you do not wish to share with the app </span></span>
<span id="cb5-13">          ),</span>
<span id="cb5-14">          <span class="at" style="color: #657422;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">tags =</span> <span class="fu" style="color: #4758AB;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">c</span>(<span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"example"</span>, <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"IRIS"</span>),</span>
<span id="cb5-15">          <span class="at" style="color: #657422;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">type =</span> <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"rds"</span>,</span>
<span id="cb5-16">          <span class="at" style="color: #657422;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">force_identical_write =</span> <span class="cn" style="color: #8f5902;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">TRUE</span> <span class="co" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;"># forces rewrite with changed metadata. otherwise only over writes if data itself has changed.</span></span>
<span id="cb5-17">)</span></code></pre></div></div>
</div>
<p>check out the pin’s metadata</p>
<div class="cell">
<div class="code-copy-outer-scaffold"><div class="sourceCode cell-code" id="cb6" style="background: #f1f3f5;"><pre class="sourceCode r code-with-copy"><code class="sourceCode r"><span id="cb6-1">meta <span class="ot" style="color: #003B4F;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">&lt;-</span> <span class="fu" style="color: #4758AB;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">pin_meta</span>(board, <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"IRIS"</span>)</span>
<span id="cb6-2">meta</span></code></pre></div></div>
</div>
</section>
<section id="add-pin-to-the-app" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="add-pin-to-the-app">Add pin to the app</h2>
<p>so now the pin is officially in the pins folder and should have the correct metadata.</p>
<p>the next step to get it to show up in the app is to add it to the pin called <code>metadata_list</code> that I created for each study.</p>
<p>this exists because mapping over each pin and reading its data in real time was slowing down the app. so we do this before hand; outside of the app. But it means a pin will not show up in the app until this list has been refreshed by running this code</p>
<div class="cell">
<div class="code-copy-outer-scaffold"><div class="sourceCode cell-code" id="cb7" style="background: #f1f3f5;"><pre class="sourceCode r code-with-copy"><code class="sourceCode r"><span id="cb7-1">list.of.pins <span class="ot" style="color: #003B4F;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">&lt;-</span> <span class="fu" style="color: #4758AB;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">pin_list</span>(board)</span>
<span id="cb7-2">metas <span class="ot" style="color: #003B4F;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">&lt;-</span> purrr<span class="sc" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">::</span><span class="fu" style="color: #4758AB;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">map</span>(list.of.pins, purrr<span class="sc" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">::</span><span class="fu" style="color: #4758AB;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">possibly</span>(<span class="at" style="color: #657422;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">.f =</span> \(x) <span class="fu" style="color: #4758AB;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">pin_meta</span>(board, x), </span>
<span id="cb7-3">                                           <span class="at" style="color: #657422;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">otherwise=</span> <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"error"</span>))</span>
<span id="cb7-4"> </span>
<span id="cb7-5"></span>
<span id="cb7-6"><span class="fu" style="color: #4758AB;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">pin_write</span>( <span class="at" style="color: #657422;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">board =</span> board, metas, <span class="at" style="color: #657422;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">name =</span> <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"metadata_list"</span>, <span class="at" style="color: #657422;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">type =</span> <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"rds"</span>)</span></code></pre></div></div>
</div>
</section>
<section id="look-at-the-metadata_list" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="look-at-the-metadata_list">look at the metadata_list</h2>
<p>if you are curious about what is in the metadata_list pin you can find out with:</p>
<div class="cell">
<div class="code-copy-outer-scaffold"><div class="sourceCode cell-code" id="cb8" style="background: #f1f3f5;"><pre class="sourceCode r code-with-copy"><code class="sourceCode r"><span id="cb8-1">mdl <span class="ot" style="color: #003B4F;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">&lt;-</span> <span class="fu" style="color: #4758AB;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">pin_read</span>(board, <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"metadata_list"</span>)</span>
<span id="cb8-2">mdl <span class="sc" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">|&gt;</span> <span class="fu" style="color: #4758AB;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">glimpse</span>()</span></code></pre></div></div>
</div>
</section>
<section id="code-from-the-app" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="code-from-the-app">code from the app</h2>
<p>if you are wondering why these steps are necessary the code for the app may be good to look at:</p>
<div class="code-copy-outer-scaffold"><div class="sourceCode" id="overview" style="background: #f1f3f5;"><pre class="sourceCode R code-with-copy"><code class="sourceCode r"><span id="overview-1">    <span class="cf" style="color: #003B4F;
background-color: null;
font-weight: bold;
font-style: inherit;">if</span> (<span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"metadata_list"</span><span class="sc" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">%in%</span>all.pins <span class="sc" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">==</span> <span class="cn" style="color: #8f5902;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">TRUE</span>) {</span>
<span id="overview-2">      metas <span class="ot" style="color: #003B4F;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">&lt;-</span> <span class="fu" style="color: #4758AB;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">pin_read</span>(values<span class="sc" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">$</span>hi, <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"metadata_list"</span>)</span>
<span id="overview-3">    }</span>
<span id="overview-4">    <span class="cf" style="color: #003B4F;
background-color: null;
font-weight: bold;
font-style: inherit;">else</span>{</span>
<span id="overview-5">      metas <span class="ot" style="color: #003B4F;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">&lt;-</span> purrr<span class="sc" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">::</span><span class="fu" style="color: #4758AB;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">map</span>(all.pins, </span>
<span id="overview-6">                          <span class="fu" style="color: #4758AB;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">possibly</span>(<span class="at" style="color: #657422;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">.f =</span> \(x) <span class="fu" style="color: #4758AB;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">pin_meta</span>(values<span class="sc" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">$</span>hi, x)))</span>
<span id="overview-7">    }</span>
<span id="overview-8">    </span>
<span id="overview-9">    values<span class="sc" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">$</span>ups  <span class="ot" style="color: #003B4F;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">&lt;-</span> <span class="fu" style="color: #4758AB;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">data.frame</span>(</span>
<span id="overview-10">      <span class="at" style="color: #657422;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">names =</span> <span class="fu" style="color: #4758AB;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">map</span>(metas, <span class="sc" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">~</span><span class="fu" style="color: #4758AB;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">pluck</span>(., <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"name"</span>, </span>
<span id="overview-11">                                <span class="at" style="color: #657422;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">.default =</span> <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"skip"</span>)) <span class="sc" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">%&gt;%</span> <span class="fu" style="color: #4758AB;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">unlist</span>(),</span>
<span id="overview-12">      <span class="at" style="color: #657422;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">upload =</span><span class="fu" style="color: #4758AB;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">map</span>(metas, <span class="sc" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">~</span><span class="fu" style="color: #4758AB;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">pluck</span>(., <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"user"</span>, <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"Upload"</span>, </span>
<span id="overview-13">                                <span class="at" style="color: #657422;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">.default =</span> <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"FALSE"</span>))<span class="sc" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">%&gt;%</span> </span>
<span id="overview-14">        <span class="fu" style="color: #4758AB;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">unlist</span>(),</span>
<span id="overview-15">      <span class="at" style="color: #657422;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">tags =</span> <span class="fu" style="color: #4758AB;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">map</span>(metas, <span class="sc" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">~</span><span class="fu" style="color: #4758AB;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">pluck</span>(., <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"tags"</span>,  </span>
<span id="overview-16">                               <span class="at" style="color: #657422;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">.default =</span> <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"FALSE"</span>) <span class="sc" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">%&gt;%</span> </span>
<span id="overview-17">                   <span class="fu" style="color: #4758AB;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">paste</span>(<span class="at" style="color: #657422;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">collapse =</span> <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">","</span>)) <span class="sc" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">%&gt;%</span> <span class="fu" style="color: #4758AB;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">unlist</span>(),</span>
<span id="overview-18">      <span class="at" style="color: #657422;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">ext =</span> <span class="fu" style="color: #4758AB;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">map</span>(metas, <span class="sc" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">~</span><span class="fu" style="color: #4758AB;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">pluck</span>(., <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"file"</span>,</span>
<span id="overview-19">                              <span class="at" style="color: #657422;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">.default =</span> <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"rds"</span>)) <span class="sc" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">|&gt;</span> <span class="fu" style="color: #4758AB;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">unlist</span>()</span>
<span id="overview-20">    )</span></code></pre></div></div>
<p>basically, for every study folder, the code looks for a pin called metadata_list and if it exists, reads it in. If it doesn’t exist then it takes a minute to map over all the pins in a folder and read in the metadata for them while the app is live (this can take a long time depending on the number of pins in a folder.)</p>
<p>and later on in the app the code populates the drop down choices with only the names of pins that have an Upload = TRUE value.</p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://srwis.github.io/personal_site/posts/pins_tut/</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
